# Chris A. Shurtleff

2120 Adair Drive • Knoxville, TN 37918 • (801) 616-1946 • cshurtle@vols.utk.edu

# **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

Data scientist with a physical science background and three years of experience in data analysis. Strong quantitative skills in programming and statistics gained through educational background and work experience. Charismatic leader with strong communication and interpersonal skills. Expertise areas: Programming, Statistics, Computational Models.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Tennessee, Haslam College of Business

Knoxville, TN

Master of Science, Business Analytics, GPA 3.7/4.0

December 2017

**Brigham Young University** 

Provo, UT

Bachelor of Science, Geology (Minor: Business Management), GPA 3.5/4.0

April 2016

### **EXPERIENCE**

Boeing Company Warner Robins, GA

Data Science Intern

May 2017 – Present

- Collaborated with subject matter experts to produce an analytics tool (using Oracle SQL and Tableau) to enable quick comparison of C-17 fleet performance before and after maintenance, replacing expensive manual comparison.
- Developed separate analytics tool (using Oracle SQL and python) to enable quick comparison of C-17 aircraft performance, improving Boeing's ability to serve the U.S. Air Force.
- Took initiative as an embedded data scientist among aircraft maintenance subject matter experts in a customer-facing environment, upgrading the capabilities of the C-17 fleet support in providing quality analysis.

University of Tennessee Knoxville, TN

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2016 – May 2017

- Wrote Python scripts to automate data scrubbing and transfer from a given format to a relational database format used to test open-source data mining software.
- Proofread academic and technical papers for publication in scientific and trade journals. I engaged in independent research to understand cutting-edge techniques in data science to provide top-quality proofreading.

#### **Brigham Young University**

Provo, UT

Research Assistant

September 2014 – April 2016

- Created a multivariate regression model using MATLAB scripts as well as a data visualization for a major geochemistry conference and an article in a top tier Geochemistry journal.
- Collaborated with a group of eight researchers to produce a computer model of mineral surface chemistry we are publishing in a series of articles in major Geochemistry publications.

#### SKILLS

Computer: Python, R, C++, Matlab, SQL, ArcGIS, AMPL, Tableau, SAS, pyspark

Math: Statistics, Model development

Language: Fluent Portuguese, Conversational Spanish

# **ACTIVITIES**

Project manager for capstone project with Capital One

Fall 2017

Member: European Association of Geochemistry

**Summer 2015** 

Presented at Goldschmidt Geochemistry Conference in Prague

**Summer 2015** 

Hobbies: hiking, snowboarding, rock climbing, kayaking and anything else to enjoy the outdoors.

## **HONORS**

University of Tennessee Assistantship Grant

Member: Phi Kappa Phi and Phi Eta Sigma Honor Societies Alvina Soffel Barret Merit-based Scholarship recipient